AURO SOLUTION DEMONSTRATION -APPLIED TO SEED 01
The terminal command to launch the solution is:
ros2  launch solution solution_nav2_launch.py
My solution involves a two-robot collaborative system. The objective is to replace a nearby red item with a blue one, which will spawn it closer and reduce the time it takes to collect
blues in the long run while maximizing score.
The robots work together to locate a blue item with an unknown position
by setting custom waypoints, inspired by virtual pheromones in swarm robotics.
Initially, the target item is red. Once a red item is spotted
using camera vision, the robot determines its next action.
In this case, both robots adjusts their velocity to approach the red items.
When the robot gets close enough that it can no longer detect the item,
it moves onwards and checks if it has collected the desired item.
Robot 2 has approached red and will move onward to collect it
Once both robots have collected a red item, they set their next target - a blue item to swap with the red one.
Robot1 is struggling to find a blue. It uses vision to avoid greens if it gets too close.
If no blues are seen robots search - moving forward, turning or scanning in place
to look for the target item.
To shorten the time taken to search for a blue item, the robots communicate via waypoints / item marks
Robot2 has found a blue and will publish a waypoint. Meanwhile Robot1 continues to look for a blue. Looks like Robot1 has received the waypoint. It will now navigate to the robot1 pose to
collect a blue instead of blindly searching.
This significantly reduces the time it takes for each robot to find a blue item
While Robot1 navigates to the waypoint, Robot2 has already
collected the blue. It will now start navigating back to home.
The return coordinates are updated to align with the Y-coordinate where the red item was collected. This ensures the robot returns home near the newly swapped blue.
During navigation, a robot must avoid all other items to ensure proper swapping.
A custom node manipulates the lidar data with items detected via vision so that
the robot can detect and avoid items as obstacles on the map while using nav2.
You can see items appear as obstacles on the map in RVizz
for Robot1.
There are cases where it does not detect in time such as when an item is too close.
Hence, as a failsafe, the Robot1  pauses until the item is swapped back in place.
Robot1 however, successfully manages to detect the red cluster
in the middle lane and replans a path to avoid them as shown in RVizz.
Unlike returning home/waypoints - Item collection and searching is done
without Nav2. Greens are avoided. Static obstacles are avoided by turning once
LIDAR scan thresholds are breached.
To prevent deadlocks when turning randomly,
my solution remembers the previous turn angle, ensuring continuous turns.
Once the robots reach the home zone,
the blue item has swapped with the initial red and is now closer to home.
The robots know via the item log that a blue has been collected. They set their
target to blue and scan their surroundings until they detect a nearby blue item, which
they then collect and return home.
Robot2 now collects the closest blue
Both robots now have a blue close by and will simply
collect and return with the closest blue.
By design this process now repeats, with the robots spending less time finding a blue item,
thus minimizing the time taken to find and collect a blue (the highest valued item)
while maximizing score for 2 robots
There are minor inconsistencies though. Due to how clustered the reds are close to each other
and the blue spawning at a random point sometimes Robots will drop the item and pause
Similarly, if blue spawns behind a red then the target is dynamically updated to red.
After which robot collects a nearly blue again.
Despite this, the time taken to collect blue and
maximization of scores is significantly reduced overall.
This solution's strength lies in its ability to swap with a nearby red
and collaboratively locate a blue cluster in less time using waypoints.
After this time consuming initial swap it is smooth sailing
as the time taken to find a blue is significantly and consistently reduced.
While this does not represent reality it takes advantage of the
simulation by applying a creative strategy